Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lawrence Morton papers
1908-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1522
42.5 linear feet (85 boxes, 1 oversize folder, 50 oversize boxes)
Lawrence Morton (1904-1987) played the organ for silent movies and studied in New York before moving to Los Angeles, California, in 1940. He was a music critic for Script magazine, was the executive director of Evenings on the Roof, director of the Ojai Music Festival and curator of music at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art. The collection consists of books, articles, musical scores, clippings, manuscripts, and correspondence related to Lawrence Morton and his activities and friends in the Southern California music scene.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Lawrence Morton, 1987.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9924702923606533
Biographical History
Morton was born in 1904; he played the organ for silent movies and studied in New York before moving to Los Angeles, California, in 1940; wrote music criticism for Script magazine; executive director, Evenings on the Roof (later renamed Monday Evening Concerts), 1952-71; director of the Ojai Music Festival; as curator of music at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art, he staged several Bing Concerts each year; died in 1987.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of books, articles, musical scores, clippings, manuscripts, and correspondence related to Lawrence Morton and his activities and friends in the Southern California music scene. Includes Morton's Igor Stravinsky bibliography and an assemblage of Stravinsky icons made up of photographs, reproductions, and original portraits of the composer. Also includes Morton's diary from his 1956 journey to Europe for the premiere of Stravinsky's Canticum Sacrum in Venice, Italy. Also contains manuscripts and drafts of Morton's published works, including chapters of an unfinished Stravinsky biography and articles for The musical quarterly, Tempo, and Notes. Includes materials related to his involvement with the Evenings on the Roof (later called Monday Evening Concerts), the Ojai Festival, and the Bing Concerts at the Los Angeles County Museum.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence
Biographical
Manuscripts by L.M.
Research material
Related Material
Monday evening concerts: Interview of Lawrence Morton [oral history transcript] / Adelaide G. Tulser, interviewer. UCLA Library Special Collections, Center for Oral History Research interview, 1973. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Lawrence Morton Collection of Materials Relating to the Monday Evening Concerts (Collection 965). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Concerts -- California -- Los Angeles.; Musicologists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Morton, Lawrence -- Archives; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971.
- Correspondence
  - Anderson, T.J., 1976.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Antoniou, Theodor., 1967-1969.; 2 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aitken, Hugh., 1977-1978.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Babbitt, Milton., August 28, 1961; n.d.; 3 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    1961: I have not yet seen the Stravinskys, although I certainly hope to.....
  - Berger, Arthur., 1955-1961.; 3 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Berio, Luciano and Cathy [Berberian]., 1960-1964.; 6 items, 8 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    December 22,1964(?): Incidentally, he [Berio] spent two days with Igorissimo (Stravinsky to you) in Rome and Paris and needless to say, they got drunk....
  - Berman, Eugene., February 16, 1960; July 23, 1964; September 17, 1968.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    July 23, 1964: Sorry to hear that Igor was again not well and still insists on making these killing concert tours... also September 17.
  - Birtwistle. Composer's notes on Tragedia., n.d.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blackwood, Easley., 1966-1967.; 4 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Boulanger, Nadia., April 27, July 29, August 3, 1959; September 23, 1963; May 28, October 3, 1969; September 2, 1970; n.d.; 10 items, 14 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    3 letters are from Boulanger's assistant A. Dieudorine.
  - de la Vega, Aurelio., 1970.; 1 item, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Haieff, Alexi., 1971.; 2 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    1: After the sad Stravinsky news... 2: I spoke to Vera S. on the telephone when they were going to Venice....
  - Goehr, Alexander., 1967-1969.; 6 items, 7 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dwyer, Doriot Anthony., 1989 [sic].; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Collaer, Paul., n.d.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Note on business card.
  - Daunton, Frank., 1973.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budd, Harold., 1974-1975.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chavez, Carlos., August 1, 1968.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Glock, William., 1973-1974.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Castiglioni, Niccolo., 1967-1968.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - De Carvalho, Eleazar., 1968.; 6 items, 9 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    1 item is program.
  - Clementi, ??., 1964.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harris, Roy., July 26, 1944; February 18, 1949; May 23, 1953.; 3 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Horne, Marilyn., January 23, February 24, 1960(?); November 5, 1981.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 23: How's Robert?...If I come to Ojai to protect Bob from you, who'll protect me from him! November 5: This is the third Jocasta...turn down..
  - Hullmay(?), Robin., December 27, 1981.; 1 item, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Very different was the saga of frustration in trying to reach Robert Craft..
  - Horne, Lena. [postmark]., 1970; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Response to a sympathy note on the death of her husband.
  - Helm, Everett., 1958-1959, 1961.; 5 items, 8 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Huber, Klaus., January 13, 1964; January 22, 1968.; 2 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Huxley, Aldous., 1955 Kam [sic] 22; October 29, 1958.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    October 29 I am glad to hear that you are to do a book on our old friend and shall be delighted to testify to the Guggenheim people....
  - Malipiero, G. Frances., 1960, n.d.; 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Moran, Robert., 1965.; 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miroglio, Francis., 1975-1981.; 5 items, 10 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Merriman, Nan., 1964.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - McCarty, Clifford., 1951-1953.; 22 items, 31 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    re Film Composers in America.
  - Mata, Eduardo., 1978.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Masson, Gerard., 1969.; 3 items, 7 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - de Mauziarly (?), Marcelle., 1950, 1968.; 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ligeti, Gyorgy., 1968.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lang, Paul Henry., November 13, 1958;May 6, 1959; June 24, no year.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    November 13 re Guggenheim, May 6 The musical world is full of pedestrians and snobs.... Just take a look at...Craft and Stravinsky..
  - Kay, Ulysses., 1976.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kagel, Mauricio., 1965.; 1 item, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jones, Charles., 1948-1949.; 6 items, 6 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Thor., 1948-1953.; 9 items, 9 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    September 11 & September 22, 1950 are from Johnson's secretary Esther Waltenburger.
  - Jacobs, Paul., 1978.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Sorry for taking Mr. White at his word....
  - Johnson, Locksen (?)., 1955-1956.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lockspeiser, Edward., 1960.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Stravinsky/Debussy relationship.
  - Nordheim, Arne., 1969-1970.; 5 items, 8 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pisk, Dr. Paul A., 1981.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - de Pablo, Luis., 1966-1973.; 13 items, 21 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newman, Arnold., 1984.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    re photos used and not used in Bravo Stravinsky.
  - Parrenin, Jaques., 1968, n.d.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Piston, Walter., May 16, 1948.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Previn, Andre., May 28, 1974; October 7, 1980; December 24, 1983; March 13, 1984.; 4 items, 6 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pousseur, Henri., 1966.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Porten (?), Andrew., 1986.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rabe, Folke., 1967.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Reich, Steve., December 26, 1974; May 1, 1975; May 13, 1975; January 29, 1980.; 4 items, 7 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    May 12, 1975: Reich comments on Stravinsky.
  - Reigger, Wallingford., 1955.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rosen, Jerry., 1965-1966.; 5 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Samuel, Gerhard., 1977-1984.; 2 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sauguet, Henri., 1965.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Schnittke, A., 1970.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Reynolds, Roger., 1966-1969.; 11 item, 12 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Schuller, Gunther., 1965 January 2.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    After my encounter with Stravinsky-Craft-Libman-Hurok...
  - Shapey, Ralph., 1966-1967.; 10 items, 13 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Shifrin, Seymour., 1965-1966.; 6 items, 6 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Silverman, Stanley., 1967.; 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Smit, Leo., 1980-1986.; 15 items, 22 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Two references to Stravinsky stamp.
  - Stevens, Denis., 1961.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    I had no idea of your present address until Robert Craft sent it to me...
  - Stevens, Halsey., 1953-1968.; 13 items, 14 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    1960 February 15 How is the search for Stravinsky going? I hear in a roundabout fashion that it leads to rendezvous with Ingrid Berman et al....
  - Sullivan, Barry., 1981.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Szigeti, Joseph., 1956.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Program listing a local Szigeti performance of the Duo concertant.
  - Thomson, Virgil., 1947 June 27, 1949 May 12, 1970 February 18, 1981 August 14, 1981 September 4.; 5 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    1981 letters are from Thomason's secretary, Louis Rispoli.
  - L.M. to Thomson., 1947 June 15, 1970 February 4, 1970 February 28, 1981 August 10.; 4 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    1947 re L.M. visit to Schoenberg.
  - Toch, Ernst., 1949 October 26, 1962 September 5, 1962 December 6.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - T..... (?) [illegible]., 1955.; 5 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Vlad, Roman., 1955.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Walker, George., 1976.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Wolff, Christian., 1962.; 1 item, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Xennakis, Janis., 1964.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yun, Isang., 1966-1967.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Zeisl, Eric., 1953 April 26, 1953 May 11, n.d. [1948?].; 3 items, 4 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - L.M. to Zeisl., 1953 May 6.; 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Amy, Gilbert., 1963-1969.; 7 items, 13 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    1968 December 6, 1969 February 6.
  - L.M. to Gilbert Amy., 1968.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Exchange re an early Stravinsky essay, probably by C.A. Cingria.
  - Boone, Charles., 1984-1987.; 32 items, 50 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1954-1964.; 25 items, 54 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Final two letters were dictated to a secretary.
    1962 September 2, November 11, December 17, 1963 February 12, 1964 June 25, November 15.
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1965-1968.; 26 items, 56 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    1966 November 12, 1967 April 22, August 18, October 29, November 12.
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1969.; 7 items, 17 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    1969 November 11 (programming).
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1970-1973.; 24 items, 45 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Includes two letters from Boulez's secretary, Astrid Schirmer.
    1970 January 30, 1971 September 8 (Postmark).
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1979-1980.; 23 items, 48 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes 9 letters from Boulez's assistant Astrid Schirmer, 1 from his secretary Nancy Hartman, 1 from Marguerite (?) and 1 from Jeanne Cuevalier.
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1977 April 5.; 1 item, 6 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Address by Pierre Boulez. This version has been 'edited' by L. Morton for publication in the journal of the Institute. [Arnold Schoenberg].
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1981-1983.; 19 items, 49 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Includes 3 letters from Astrid Schirmer.
    1981 January 8, March 16 (Includes photocopied letters from S. MacCrindle, C. Matthews and R. Craft re early versions of Les Noces, March 27(Snowman), December 7.
  - Boulez, Pierre., 1984-1986. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    7 letters from Astrid Schirmer, 4 from Jeanne Cuevalier, 2 from Nancy Hartman and 2 invoices from Universal Edition.
    1985 April 30, August 5.
  - L.M. to Pierre Boulez., 1954-1969.; 45 items, 53 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    1954 July 9, 1958 June 4, 1959 April 1, 1961 December 20, 1962 October 19, December 13, 1964 October 28, 1965 July 18, 1966 January 4, October 24.
  - L.M. to Pierre Boulez., 1970-1981.; 15 items, 20 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    1 item is a newspaper clipping.
    1970 March 9, 1981 March 14-15, April 15-16 re 1917 Les Noces (See Box 50 for Noces scores).
  - L.M. to Boulez., n.d.; 3 items, 3 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Boulez Festschrift--Correspondence regarding 60th birthday concert for Pierre Boulez (with English translations from the original German)., 18 items, 41 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cummings ist der dichter, by Lawrence Morton., n.d.; 3 items, 54 pieces. Photocopied typescript w/ holograph corrections. Two in English, one in German. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Reference to Les Noces and Requiem canticles in last paragraph.
  - L.M. to Katharina Schmidt re Homage a Boulez., 1985 February 1.; 1 item, 1 piece. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Loan of photographs to the festival.
  - Boulez Miscellaneous., 1963-1977.; 13 items, 22 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes rehearsal schedules, visa materials, contracts, concert invitation, letters from agents.
  - Cage, John., 1961-1977.; 9 items, 14 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes flyer/program and ticket reservation for concert 1965 January 12.
  - L.M. to John Cage., 1961-1962.; 6 items, 6 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    1962 January 9, January 25 re the inclusion of a Stravinsky work (in honor of his 80th birthday on Cage program.
  - Carter, Elliott., 1954-1984 & 3 n.d.; 14 items, 16 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Including 2 letters from Helen Carter.
    1954 December 29, 1961 September 15, September 25, November 26, December 11, 1962 January 15, February 3, November 2, 1979 April 4, 1984 February 19.
  - L.M. to Elliott Carter., 1961-1962.; 8 items, 10 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    1961 October 18 re Sacre, October 27, December 7, 1962 January 8, January 27, February 6 re Craft performance of Carter's Double Concerto.
  - Chihara, Paul., 1967-1970.; 13 items, 23 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    2 newspaper clippings.
  - Copland, Aaron., 1944-1956.; 18 items, 21 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Copland, Aaron., 1957.; 16 items, 21 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    1957 April 24, May 1.
  - Copland, Aaron., 1958-1959.; 15 items, 24 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    1959 April 28.
  - Copland, Aaron., 1960-1973.; 31 item, 46 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    1962 November 20.
  - Copland, Aaron., 1974-1980.; 20 items, 37 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Included is Celebrating Copland by Lawrence Morton from Upbeat November 1985.
  - Copland, Aaron., 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - L.M. to Copland., 1954-1956.; 9 items, 10 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    1956 March 30, December 12.
  - L.M. to Copland., 1957.; 19 items, 22 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    1957 January 7, April 10, April 22, May 9.
  - L.M. to Copland., 1958.; 14 items, 16 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    October 17, October 18.
  - L.M. to Copland, Aaron., 1960-1976.; 15 items, 18 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    1960 January 26, April 5, 1961 May 9, 1970 July 3.
  - L.M. to Copland., 2 items, 2 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Boulez, Pierre., n.d.; 11 item, 12 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    The final undated letter includes Boulez's opinion of Robert Craft.
  - Miscellaneous letters and correspondence to Lawrence Morton, circa 1941 - 1987 (Box 137)
  - Letters, correspondence, and miscellaneous papers, circa 1935 - 1986 (Box 138)
- Biographical
  - Datebooks and a European diary (1956)
    - L.M.'s daily appointment books & diary of trip to Europe with the Stravinskys., 1963-1987 1956 (Box 124)
  - Memorabilia
    - Programs relating to L.M.'s arrangements of music and appearances as a musicologist. (Box 5)
    - David Raksin--A Greeting card with a gold coin attached a monsieur Lindi Soir - We love you every other night of the week* (Box 101)
      *Too!.
    - Musical birthday greeting from the Stalveys., Unmarked envelope. (Box 102)
    - A file of documents relating to the Arnold Schoenberg Institute on the campus of the University of Southern California. (Box 127)
    - Yearbook-style notes and signatures to Morton, undated (Box 128, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Two sheets of loose paper with yearbook-style notes and signatures to Morton on both sides.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Performing Arts Zubin Mehta Los Angeles Philharmonic ten years together, (December) 1971. (Box 64)
      No Morton notes in this issue.
    - Miscellaneous papers including photos, correspondence to Lawrence Morton, copies, and scripts (Box 139)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, programs, program notes, and bound copies of "Lawrence Morton Remembered". (Box 140)
    - Lawrence Morton, script, 1940-1941 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence Morton, script, 1942-1943 (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Lawrence Morton, script, 1944-1945 (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Lawrence Morton, script, 1946 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Lawrence Morton, script, 1947-1948 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Lawrence Morton, counter point (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Lawrence Morton, frontier (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Documents MEC (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Lawrence Morton, speeches (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Lawrence Morton, unpublished articles (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence Morton, bibliography (Box 141, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 141, Folder 12)
    - Mr. L. Morton: Laurel Leaf Award, 1966 (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - Lawrence Morton: Retirement from Monday Evening Concerts (MEC) (Box 141, Folder 14)
  - Program and Liner Notes
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Prokofiev Violin Concertos., 1966 February. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Primrose Album: Ernest Bloch., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Marlowe's Vivaldi-Bach Concertos., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Hindemith and Toch Symphonies. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Liszt and Chopin Concertos. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Debussy piano pieces., 1958 (27 March). (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Firkusny Czech Polka and Dances. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Bach Chaconne and Paganiniana. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Pennario Album: Chopin Fantaisie-impromptu in C-sharp minor.Mendelssohn: Rondo Capriccioso in E major, Opus 14. Debussy Golliwog's Cakewalk & The Girl with the Flaxen Hair. (Box 64)
      Kreisler-Rachmaninoff: Liebesfreud. Chopin: Etude in E major Opus 10, no.3. Prokofiev: March from The love of Three Oranges.
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Beethoven Sonatas: Waldstein and Opus 109. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Pennario: Sonatas by Bartok, Prokofiev, Rozsa., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Lt. Kije (Prokofiev) and Hary Janos (Kodaly)., 1958 November-January 1959. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Tchaikowsky Serenade & Prokofieff Classical Symphony., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Britten: Young Person's Guide to the Orchestra and Dohnanyi: Variations on a Nursery Rhyme. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Mendelssohn: Concerto in E minor & Bruch: Concerto in G minor. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Hollywood Quartet Album: Schumann and Hummel. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Chopin Scherzos., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Glazunov's The Seasons., 1961 (January). (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Paul Hindemith: Sonata for two pianos, four hands (1942), Sonata for one piano, four hands (1938). (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Walter Piston Sonata for flute and piano. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Ravel Rapsodie espagnol., 1958 (27 January). (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Carmen and Faust orchestral suites. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Schubert Trio in E flat., 1958 (25 February). (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Rachmaninoff Cello Sonata Opus 19., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Bach G-minor Sonata and D-minor Suite. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Death and transfiguration and Till Eulenspiegel. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Album of Overtures., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Pennario Waltz Album (Ravel, Delibes-Dohnanyi, etc.)., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Milstein album: Lalo and Prokofieff. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Brahms: Handel Variations and Paganini Variations. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Stokowski's Music for Strings., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Beethoven-Bach Album., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Almeida Album: Impression do Brasil. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Liszt-Chopin album by Kentner., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Chopin Impromptus and Ballades. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for The firebird and Petrouchka. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for The new world of the guitar., 1957 30 July. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Goldmark Violin Concerto., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Loeffler's Pagan Pome., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Glazu November and Dvorak Violin Concertos. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Stokowski's Landmarks of a distinguished Career. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Piano Encores., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Holst: The Planets., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Beethoven Symphony VII., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Franck and Schumann works--Pennario. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Debussy Nocturnes., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Carter, Elegy, Ives, Scherzo, Duke, Quartet, Mennin, Quartet., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Sibelius Symphony II., n.d. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner for Kentner's (I mean Beethoven's) Appassionata and Waldstein. (Box 64)
    - Morton, Lawrence--Liner notes--Prokofiev: Quintet Opus 39., n.d. (Box 64)